<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: video | Musings of an 8-bit Vet]]></title>
  <link href="http://bayendor.github.io/blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bayendor.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-23T16:19:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://bayendor.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Bayendor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weaving Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/weaving-code/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-23T16:03:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/weaving-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently came across the most amazing piece of video footage while watching
a documentary on the technology used during the Apollo missions of the late
1960&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>That era was a little bit like an alternate decade of the 21st century that
sort of just showed up in the middle of the 20th century.  In addition to
tremendous leaps in aviation and space-flight that decade gave us advances
 in medical, material, and computer science.</p>

<p>To put it in perspective, the working memory of the navigation computer for
the Apollo missions was just 72 kilobytes!  Things that we take for granted
now had to be invented from scratch, including interrupt driven multi-processing
algorithms and reliable data storage.</p>

<p>For a fascinating look at how the latter was solved, watch this video:</p>

<p><code><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://bayendor.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/P12r8DKHsak" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></code></p>

<p>For more about this amazing and lost technology see the Wikipedia entry: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Core_rope_memory">Core Rope Memory</a></p>

<p>On a separate note, this is a fascinating and possibly forgotten example of
diversity in coding.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails and TDD Screencasts Worth Watching]]></title>
    <link href="http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/screencasts-that-teach-rails-and-tdd/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-16T14:53:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/screencasts-that-teach-rails-and-tdd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick post to describe two excellent on-line resources that I have
found to be extremely helpful as we enter the mid-point of our training at
<a href="http://davincicoders.com/building-the-toolbelt-of-a-junior-ruby-on-rails-developer/">DaVinci Coders</a>.</p>

<p>The first is Ryan Bates' excellent <a href="http://railscasts.com/">RailsCasts</a> series
of Ruby on Rails screencasts.  While this is a subscription service, Ryan has
generously made many of his older screencasts available for free.  The amount
of technical expertise and pro-level tips is absolutely amazing for me as a
junior Rails dev.  Prior to this I had no real notion of some of the topics
that RailsCasts covers, but now that I&rsquo;m working with Rails every day, this
content is absolutely priceless.</p>

<p>The second is the CodeShip series called <a href="http://blog.codeship.io/category/testing-tuesday">Testing Tuesday</a>.  As the name suggests, these are short video
tutorials on various aspects of TDD and BDD tools and skills, like RSpec,
Cucumber, and other languages beyond Ruby and Rails.  Even better, these are
free.  They are also posted online at <a href="https://vimeo.com/codeship">Vimeo</a>.</p>

<p>The beauty of both of these resources &ndash; and I&rsquo;m sure there are others &ndash; is that
they are short and to the point. Each are about 10 minutes long, and address
a problem or provide an overview of a technique that you can put to work right
away.</p>

<p>Next time you are browsing the web and watching <a href="www.youtube.com">YouTube</a>
 videos, take a look at one of these resources and learn something that will
 make you a better developer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agile is the new black]]></title>
    <link href="http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/agile-is-the-new-black/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T20:14:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://bayendor.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/agile-is-the-new-black</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>What do you despise?  By this are you truly known.</p><footer><strong>Frank Herbert</strong> <cite>Dune</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>We hear the term &ldquo;agile&rdquo; all the time in the development world.  What does it
really mean?  Everything seems to have the term agile attached to it.</p>

<p>It came up in class tonight as we were introduced to Pivotal Tracker, and the
paradigm behind it.</p>

<p>Sometimes you can figure out what something is by what it is not.  A few weeks
ago I came across a video on Vimeo that addressed this.  Enjoy&hellip;</p>

<p><code>
  <iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/68689393?byline=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
</code></p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/68689393">Fred George - Agile is the new black - Railsberry 2013</a>.</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
